原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     elingbow  哈库那玛塔塔·闲汀  屯栗子
翻译     觉得彭彭小时候超可爱的怪物君  木浅
翻译     glida  胡说大王  米维斯·糊  布塔
校对     哈库那布塔塔
时间轴   木法沙·查  丁满·嘉  噃噃  今  紫夏
后期     渔夫·渔库那满塔塔
总监     布塔
♪ 有一头狮子来了 ♪
♪ Nants ingonyama ♪
♪ 父亲 ♪
♪ Bagithi baba ♪
♪ 是的  是一头狮子 ♪
♪ Sithi uhhmm ingonyama ♪
♪ 狮子 ♪
♪ Ingonyama ♪
♪ 有一头狮子来了 ♪
♪ Nants ingonyama ♪
♪ 父亲 ♪
♪ Bagithi baba ♪
♪ 是的  是一头狮子 ♪
♪ Sithi uhhmm ingonyama ♪
♪ 狮子 ♪
♪ Ingonyama ♪
♪ 我们会征服 ♪
♪ Siyo nqoba ♪
♪ 狮子 ♪
♪ Ingonyama ♪
♪ 狮子和猎豹来到这片辽阔大地 ♪
♪ Ingonyama inengw' enamabala ♪
♪ 自我们降生于 ♪
♪ From the day we arrive ♪
♪ 这个星球 ♪
♪ On the planet ♪
♪ 眨眨眼睛  步入阳光 ♪
♪ And blinking step into the sun ♪
♪ 大千世界  包罗万象 ♪
♪ There's more to see than can ever be seen ♪
♪ 广阔天地  任我闯荡 ♪
♪ More to do than can ever be done ♪
♪ 洋洋大观  取之不尽 ♪
♪ There's far too much to take in here ♪
♪ 日新月异  百看不厌 ♪
♪ More to find than can ever be found ♪
♪ 但当旭日东升 ♪
♪ But the sun rolling high ♪
♪ 划过天际 ♪
♪ Through the sapphire sky ♪
♪ 周而复始  世事无常 ♪
♪ Keeps great and small on the endless round ♪
♪ 生生不息 ♪
♪ It's the circle of life ♪
♪ 众生皆往 ♪
♪ And it moves us all ♪
♪ 遍尝痛苦希望 ♪
♪ Through despair and hope ♪
♪ 心怀爱与信仰 ♪
♪ Through faith and love ♪
♪ 在这生命轮回 ♪
♪ Till we find our place ♪
♪ 无尽之路 ♪
♪ On the path unwinding ♪
♪ 寻得 ♪
♪ In the circle ♪
♪ 安居之所 ♪
♪ The circle of life ♪
♪ 生生不息 ♪
♪ It's the circle of life ♪
♪ 众生皆往 ♪
♪ And it moves us all ♪
♪ 遍尝痛苦希望 ♪
♪ Through despair and hope ♪
♪ 心怀爱与信仰 ♪
♪ Through faith and love ♪
♪ 在这生命轮回 ♪
♪ Till we find our place ♪
♪ 无尽之路 ♪
♪ On the path unwinding ♪
♪ 寻得 ♪
♪ In the circle ♪
♪ 安居之所 ♪
♪ The circle of life ♪
狮子王
生命并不公平
Life's not fair...
是不是  我的小朋友
is it, my little friend?
有的是天生的猎食者
While some are born to feast...
有的却一辈子活在黑暗中
others spend their lives in the dark,
乞求残羹剩饭
begging for scraps.
要我说
The way I see it...
你我没有什么差别
you and I are exactly the same.
我们都在寻找出路
We both want to find a way out.
国王驾到
The king approaches!
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
陛下要求接见
His Majesty has requested an audience.
当他驾到时  你要起身跪拜
Upon his entrance, you will rise and genuflect.
沙祖
Zazu...
你害得我丢掉了午餐
you've made me lose my lunch.
你错过了早上的仪式
You will answer to Mufasa
要向木法沙回话
for missing the ceremony this morning.
我不会向任何人回话
I answer to no one.
疤面  疤面  疤面
Scar? Scar. Scar.
别  别这么看着我
No, no. Don't look at me like that.
你饿吗  沙祖
Are you hungry, Zazu?
要不要和我一起吃个饭
Perhaps we could have a bite together!
你不能吃我
You can't eat me!
禁止捕食王宫成员
It is forbidden to eat a member of the king's court!
不  求你了  住手
No, please! Stop it!
疤面
Scar!
看看是谁屈尊降驾来探访平民了
Well, look who's come down to mingle with the commoners.
沙拉碧和我在辛巴的洗礼仪式上没看到你
Sarabi and I didn't see you at the presentation of Simba.
是今天吗
Was that today?
我不小心忘记了
Must've slipped my mind.
我当然无意对陛下或沙拉碧失礼
Of course I meant no disrespect towards His Majesty or Sarabi.
你也知道  我对王后极其尊重
As you know, I have tremendous respect for the queen.
作为国王的弟弟
As the king's brother,
你应该站在前列
you should've been first in line.
我本来在继承前列
I was first in line.
难道你忘了吗
Or don't you remember?
直到尊贵的王子诞生
That is, until the precious prince arrived.
不要背对着我  疤面
Don't turn your back on me, Scar.
不  木法沙
Oh, no, Mufasa,
你才不应该背弃我
perhaps you shouldn't turn your back on me.
你在挑战我吗
Is that a challenge?
我做梦都不敢再次挑战你
I wouldn't dream of challenging you again.
明智的选择
A wise decision.
你根本敌不过国王陛下
You are no match for His Royalness.
就智力来说  我占上风
Well, as far as brains go, I got the lion's share.
但要比蛮力
But when it comes to brute strength,
恐怕我哥哥
I'm afraid my big brother...
会永远称王
will always rule.
不是永远  疤面
Not always, Scar.
有一天  我的儿子会掌权
One day, it'll be my son who rules.
辛巴会成为你的王
Simba will be your king.
那就祝国王万岁
Then long live the king.
-我该拿他怎么办  -拜托
- What am I gonna do with him? - Oh, come on.
你我都清楚  早就该把他
We both know he should've been
流放到荣耀大地之外了
expelled from the Pride Lands long ago.
他是我弟弟  沙祖
He's my brother, Zazu.
这里是他的家
This is his home.
只要我还身居王位  就绝不会赶他走
As long as I am king, that will never change.
家家都有个难缠得主  陛下
Well, there's one in every family, sire.
我有个表哥以为自己是啄木鸟
I had a cousin who thought he was a woodpecker.
脑袋对着树猛啄
He slammed his head into trees,
但我们的喙可经不住这么折腾
and our beaks aren't built for it.
他经常得脑震荡  你要走了
He was concussed regularly. Oh, you've gone.
陛下回宫
Sire, coming back!
辛巴
Simba.
爸爸  你醒了吗
Dad, you awake?
爸爸  醒醒
Dad, wake up!
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  爸爸  爸爸
Dad, Dad, Dad!
你儿子醒了
Your son's awake.
日出之前  他是你儿子
Before sunrise, he's your son.
快点  爸爸  我们走
Come on, Dad, let's go.
你说我今天可以和你一起巡视
You said I could patrol with you today.
今天开始了
And today has started.
你保证过  起来了吗
You promised! You up?
我们出发
Let's do this!
Let's do this.
先干什么
So, what's first?
下令狩猎  驱逐邪恶入侵者
Give orders for the hunt? Chase away evil intruders?
爸爸  走错方向了
Dad! You're going the wrong way!
爸爸
Dad?
妈妈不允许我上来
I'm not supposed to go up here.
看  辛巴
Look, Simba.
阳光照耀下的一切都是我们的王国
Everything the light touches is our kingdom.
这全都由你统治吗
You rule all of that?
是的
Yes.
但国王的统治时间
But a king's time as ruler...
像太阳一样有起有落
rises and falls like the sun.
有一天  辛巴
One day, Simba...
我的太阳会落下
the sun will set on my time here...
而你则会作为新王冉冉升起
and will rise with you as the new king.
这一切都会属于我吗
All of this will belong to me?
王国不属于任何人
It belongs to no one,
但你会肩负保护它的使命
but will be yours to protect.
责任重大
A great responsibility.
阳光照耀下的一切吗
Everything the light touches?
那些树  还有那个饮水坑
Those trees? And the watering hole?
还有那座山
And that mountain?
还有那片暗影地带的尽头
And beyond those shadows?
你绝不能到那里去  辛巴
You must not go there, Simba.
可我以为国王想去哪儿就去哪儿
But I thought a king could do whatever he wants.
征服任意一片领土
Take any territory.
虽然有的王只懂得索取
While others search for what they can take...
但真正的王致力于奉献
a true king searches for what he can give.
你所见到的一切事物
Everything you see exists together
都保持着微妙的平衡
in a delicate balance.
作为国王  你要理解这种平衡
As king, you need to understand that balance...
尊重所有生物
and respect all the creatures...
不论是爬行的蝼蚁还是跳跃的羚羊
from the crawling ant to the leaping antelope.
可是爸爸  我们不是会吃羚羊吗
But, Dad, don't we eat the antelope?
是的  辛巴  先听我解释
Yes, Simba. But let me explain.
我们死后  尸体会化为青草
When we die, our bodies become the grass...
而羚羊以草为食
and the antelope eat the grass...
因此所有生物都在生命轮回中紧密相连
and so we are all connected in the great circle of life.
-陛下  -早上好  沙祖
- Sire! - Morning, Zazu.
晨间报告准备好了吗
Do you have the morning report?
是的  陛下
Yes, sire.
十只火烈鸟正在站立[表态]Ten flamingos are taking a stand.
两头长颈鹿正在交颈[打架]Two giraffe were caught necking.
据蜜蜂提供的消息[嗡嗡]The buzz from the bees...
花豹遇到了一点麻烦[斑点]is that the leopards are in a bit of a spot.
想不想来点乐子
Ready for some fun?
早上四点  小鸟鸣叫[发信]The birds are tweeting at 4:00 in the morning.
我就说  "小鸟  我们知道了"
I'm like, "Birds, we get it."
身体伏地
Stay low to the ground.
看我的吧
I got this.
注意风向  阴影
Check the wind, the shadows...
等待突袭的最佳时机
and wait for the perfect moment to pounce.
猎豹偷走了狒狒的晚餐
The cheetahs stole the baboons' dinner,
结果狒狒发狂[猩猩]and now the baboons are going ape.
当然  要我说  猎豹[谐音"骗子"]永远发不了家
Of course, as I say, cheetahs never prosper.
我就是这么想的
That's what I say.
听懂了吗  我再说一次
Do you get... I'll say it again.
猎豹永远...
Cheetahs never...
拜托  我在报新闻
Come on! It's the news!
好样的
That's very good!
陛下
Sire!
陛下  鬣狗进入了荣耀大地
Sire! Hyenas in the Pride Lands.
他们在狩猎
They're on the hunt!
沙拉碧在哪
Where's Sarabi?
她正带头应敌
She's leading the charge.
沙祖  带辛巴回家
Zazu, take Simba home.
爸爸  让我去  我能帮上忙
Dad, let me come! I can help.
不  儿子  你和其他小狮子待在一起
No, son. You stay with the other cubs.
我不是小狮子
I am not a cub.
好了
Come on.
我们回家
Let's go home.
我们到了
Here we are.
你去和其他小狮子一起玩吧
Now you go along and play with the other cubs.
真棒
Great.
如果你想猎杀成功
If you wish to kill something...
也许应该待在下风处
you might want to stay downwind.
我知道怎么狩猎  疤面叔叔
I know how to hunt, Uncle Scar.
那但愿我们永远不会被一只甲虫袭击
Well, let's hope we're never attacked by a beetle.
回你的窝里去吧  辛巴  我可不当保姆
Go back to your den, Simba. I don't babysit.
当保姆  我将会成为荣耀石的国王
Babysit? I'm gonna be the king of Pride Rock.
我爸爸带我巡视了整个王国
My dad showed me the whole kingdom.
说我将会统治一切
Said I'm going to rule it all.
是吗
Is that so?
想想看
Think about it.
等我成为国王  我必须得向你发号施令
When I'm king, I'll have to give you orders.
告诉你该做什么
Tell you what to do.
这多奇怪啊
How weird is that?
你根本想象不到
You've no idea.
你爸爸带你巡视了整个王国
So, your dad showed you the whole kingdom?
他带你去了北部边境外的暗影地带吗
Did he show you the shadows beyond the northern borders?
没有  他说我不能去那里  永远不能
No. He said I can't go there. Ever.
他说得完全没错
And he's absolutely right.
大象坟墓可不是一位年轻王子该去的地方
An elephant graveyard is no place for a young prince.
大象坟墓
An elephant graveyard?
天呐  我说得太多了
Oh, dear. I've said too much.
不过我想你迟早都会发现那里的
Though I suppose you'd have found out sooner or later...
等你成为国王统治一切
you being king and all.
你去过那里吗
You've been there?
我们都去过  那里可不是小狮子该去的地方
We've all been there. And it's no place for a cub.
那些腐烂的尸骨
All those rotting bones...
还有渗出的滚烫泥浆
and burning pools of oozing mud.
腐烂的尸骨  渗出的泥浆
Rotting bones? Oozing mud?
向我保证你会远离那里  辛巴
Promise me you'll stay away, Simba.
你可以走了
Now, you run along.
要记住
And remember...
这是我们的小秘密
it's our little secret...
陛下
Your Majesty.
娜娜  快点  我们得走了
Nala! Come on. We have to go.
-去哪儿  -饮水坑
- Where? - Watering hole.
辛巴  她正在清洁身体
Simba, she's having her bath.
你也该做清洁了
And it's time for yours.
但是  妈妈...
But, Mom...
我可以自己来
I can do it myself.
别动
Hold still.
你把我的鬣毛都弄乱了
You're messing up my mane!
来吧  耳朵后面舔一舔
Come on. Behind the ears.
别这样  妈妈
Come on, Mom!
看见了吧  全干净了  我们能走了吗
See? All clean. Can we go?
现在没有鬣狗了
There's no hyenas.
你刚刚把他们都赶跑了
You just chased them all off.
只能去饮水坑  不能跑远了
Just to the watering hole and no further.
还有要待在下风处
And stay downwind.
还有一件小事
And one more little thing.
沙祖要跟你们一起去
Zazu will be going with you.
-沙祖  -沙祖
- Zazu? - Zazu?
沙祖要跟着  否则你们不许去
Zazu goes... or you don't.
来吧  跟上  我们结成小组一起行动
Come along. Keep up. Let's move in a unit.
好了  结伴制
Okay, buddy system.
我们到底要去哪儿
So, where are we really going?
你怎么知道
How did you know?
你讨厌水
You hate the water.
我听说了这个地方  娜娜
I heard about this place, Nala.
世上最不可思议  最难以置信的...
The most incredible, amazing...
直接告诉我是哪吧
Just tell me where.
一处大象坟墓
An elephant graveyard.
那里有多远
How far is it?
不远  只要走到暗影地带就好
Not far. Just to the shadows.
但别担心  大家都去过那里
But don't worry, everyone's been there.
我们以前从来没去过那么远
We've never been that far before.
如果我们迷路了怎么办
What if we get lost?
放轻松  娜娜
Relax, Nala.
我今天早上跟着爸爸巡视了整个王国
I patrolled the entire kingdom this morning with my dad.
没什么好担心的
There's nothing to worry about.
还有一件事要担心
Well, there is one thing.
有危险逼近  有东西在向我们靠近
We have an imminent threat. Something is approaching.
等等  当我没说  那是我自己的影子
Wait, scratch that. That's my own shadow.
我们要怎么摆脱这只笨鸟
How we getting rid of the dodo?
相信我  我可以的
Trust me, I got this.
跟随我奔向自由吧
Follow me to freedom.
太感动了
How lovely it is...
看着未来的国王和他未来的王后
to see the future king with his future queen.
我感动得都要换毛了
I could just molt.
你说"未来的王后"是什么意思
What do you mean, "future queen"?
总有一天你们俩会永结同心
Well, one day the two of you will be betrothed.
喜结连理  白头偕老
Intended. Affianced.
辛巴  你懂鸟语吗
Simba, you speak bird?
结婚
Married!
拜托  总有一天你们会结婚
Come on. One day you will be married.
同彼此结为夫妻
To each other.
-这不可能  沙祖  -绝对不可能
- That's not gonna happen, Zazu. - Never ever.
娜娜和我是朋友
Nala and I are friends.
而且  她害怕犀牛
And besides, she's afraid of rhinos!
-他从来没吃过黑斑羚  -我试过一次
- And he's never eaten an impala. - I've tried it once.
我们永远不会结婚的  沙祖
We are never getting married, Zazu.
一位忽视传统的君王
A monarch who ignores tradition?
如果怀着这样的态度
With an attitude like that,
恐怕你会成为一位非常可悲的国王
I'm afraid you'll be a pretty pathetic king.
别想指挥我该去哪里
Well, I'm not letting anyone tell me where to go,
该做什么
what to do...
甚至该和谁结婚
and even who to marry.
永远不会有像我这样的国王
There will never be a king like me.
辛巴  你逃脱不了自己的宿命
Simba, you can't escape your destiny.
等着瞧吧
Just watch.
♪ 我要成为一位威武的国王 ♪
♪ I'm gonna be a mighty king ♪
♪ 敌人都小心点 ♪
♪ So enemies beware ♪
♪ 我从没见过哪位百兽之王 ♪
♪ Well, I've never seen a king of beasts ♪
♪ 身上连毛都没长全 ♪
♪ With quite so little hair ♪
♪ 我要成为前所未有的伟大国王 ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the main event like no king was before ♪
♪ 我正在学习震慑俯视 ♪
♪ I'm brushing up on looking down ♪
♪ 练习我的咆哮狮吼 ♪
♪ Working on my roar ♪
♪ 目前为止  还无法令我刮目相看 ♪
♪ Thus far a rather uninspiring thing ♪
♪ 我等不及要成为国王了 ♪
♪ Oh, I just can't wait to be king ♪
你还有很长的路要走  小主人
You have rather a long way to go, young master.
如果你以为...
If you think...
♪ 别想指挥我"该这样做" ♪
♪ No one saying "do this" ♪
我这样说的时候...
Now, when I said that...
♪ 别想指挥我"该去那里" ♪
♪ No one saying "be there" ♪
我的意思是...
What I meant was...
♪ 别想指挥我"别那样做" ♪
♪ No one saying "stop that" ♪
♪ 别想指挥我"快看这里" ♪
♪ No one saying "see here" ♪
快看这里
Now see here!
♪ 整天自由自在地奔跑 ♪
♪ Free to run around all day ♪
这绝对不可以
Well, that's definitely out.
♪ 完全按照自己的想法来 ♪
♪ Free to do it all my way ♪
♪ 我想你和我应该 ♪
♪ I think it's time that you and I ♪
♪ 来一场坦诚的谈心 ♪
♪ Arranged a heart-to-heart ♪
♪ 首先国王无需听取 ♪
♪ Kings don't need advice ♪
♪ 来自小犀鸟的建议 ♪
♪ From little hornbills for a start ♪
♪ 如果这就是君主制的未来 ♪
♪ If this is where the monarchy is headed ♪
♪ 请别把我算在内 ♪
♪ Count me out ♪
♪ 让我卸下职责  离开非洲 ♪
♪ Out of service, out of Africa ♪
♪ 我不愿浪费时间 ♪
♪ I wouldn't hang about ♪
♪ 这个孩子翅膀硬了完全失控 ♪
♪ This child is getting wildly out of wing ♪
辛巴
Simba!
♪ 我等不及要成为国王了 ♪
♪ Oh, I just can't wait to be king ♪
辛巴
Simba!
我看不见你了  辛巴
I can't see you, Simba.
你必须时刻在我的视线之内
You must be in my sight at all times.
我把他跟丢了
I've lost him!
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're doing!
你要去哪  辛巴
Where are you going, Simba?
拜托
Come on!
你躲不过我的  辛巴
You can't hide from me, Simba.
护你周全是我宣誓的职责
It is my sworn duty to keep you safe.
你好好听我说
You listen to me right now.
很抱歉在你们面前飞来飞去
I'm sorry to flutter about in your face,
你们有没有见到...他是头小狮子
have you seen... He's a little lion.
他体型很小  但很可爱
He's small, but he's cute.
♪ 大家一起向左看 ♪
♪ Everybody look left ♪
♪ 大家一起向右看 ♪
♪ Everybody look right ♪
♪ 不管你看向哪里 ♪
♪ Everywhere you look I'm ♪
♪ 我都是目光的焦点 ♪
♪ Standing in the spotlight ♪
还不行
Not yet.
♪ 让所有动物全力以赴放声高歌 ♪
♪ Let every creature go for broke and sing ♪
♪ 不论走兽还是飞禽都唱得响亮 ♪
♪ Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing ♪
我看见你在下面  我看见你在下面
I see you down there! I see you down there!
♪ 这会是辛巴国王最骄傲的放纵 ♪
♪ It's gonna be King Simba's finest fling ♪
♪ 我等不及要成为国王了 ♪
♪ Oh, I just can't wait to be king ♪
辛巴
Simba!
♪ 他等不及要成为国王了 ♪
♪ He just can't wait to be king ♪
♪ 我等不及 ♪
♪ Oh, I just can't wait ♪
♪ 等不及 ♪
♪ Just can't wait ♪
♪ 要成为国王了 ♪
♪ To be king ♪
我把他跟丢了
I've lost him!
木法沙不会轻饶我的
Mufasa's gonna have my feathers.
这可大事不妙
This is not good!
辛巴  我们真的甩掉他了
Simba, we really lost him.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
"未来的国王是一位天才"
"The future king is a genius."
你是在开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
没有你的王后  你绝对跑不出来
You would've never gotten away without your queen.
你是不是忘记了一件事
Aren't you forgetting something?
根本没有王后
There is no queen.
这话我没意见
You could say that again.
我宁愿和土豚结婚
I'd rather marry an aardvark.
祝你好运  找到愿意的那位
Good luck finding one that will say yes.
祝你好运  毫发无伤地离开这里
Good luck getting out of here without a bruising.
你尽管试试
Give it your best shot.
打倒你了
Pinned ya!
你欠我一个道歉
You owe me an apology.
绝不
Never!
打倒你了  又一次
Pinned ya. Again.
娜娜  住手
Nala, stop!
那是什么
What is that?
你可耍不了我  辛巴
You're not gonna trick me, Simba.
我知道什么也没有...
I know that there's nothing...
肯定就是这里了
This must be it.
快点
Come on!
辛巴  我们已经离荣耀大地太远了
Simba, we're way beyond the Pride Lands.
我们找到这里了  娜娜
We found it, Nala.
你知道这意味着什么吗
You know what this means?
意味着我们可以回家了
It means we can go home.
这意味着他们不会再把我们当小狮子了
It means they won't treat us like cubs anymore.
辛巴  快下来  可能有危险
Simba, get down! It could be dangerous.
危险
Danger?
我对危险嗤之以鼻
I laugh in the face of danger.
酷
Cool!
听到了吗  娜娜
You hear that, Nala?
辛巴  拜托
Simba, come on!
你已经证明了你有多勇敢
You've proved how brave you are.
太阳要下山了
Now the sun is going down,
我可不打算待在这里
I'm not just gonna sit here and...
快看呀
Well, look at this.
没想到今天会有访客
We weren't expecting guests today.
你们两头小狮子
Would you two cubs...
想留下来吃晚餐吗
like to stay for dinner?
对啊  留下来吃晚餐
Yeah, stay for dinner.
因为你们俩看着很像夜宵
'Cause you look like a midnight snack!
你就不能给我点空间吗
Can you just give me a little bit of space?
我在帮你呢
I'm helping.
我们事先都讨论好了
We have talked about this before.
我独自过来
I come in alone.
我来牵制注意力  让大家包围
I'm the lead distraction so everyone can circle.
好吧  好吧  抱歉
Okay, okay. Sorry.
别抱歉  照做就是了
Don't be sorry. Just do it.
这顿大餐
Now, this is a meal
我可是等了一辈子了
I've waited my whole life for.
拿国王的儿子当点心  真是意外之喜
What an unexpected treat, to eat the son of a king.
等等  国王  就是那个谁吗
Wait a second, the king? As in you-know-who?
统治百兽的那位
Who rules you-know-where?
木法沙可不能统治我
Mufasa does not rule me!
你不能把我怎么样
You can't do anything to me!
因为我是未来的国王
'Cause I'm the future king!
他在对我发号施令呢
He's telling me what to do.
他父亲的力量在他内心闪烁
His father's strength flickering inside.
我在想
I wonder...
那种勇敢到底是什么味道
how all that bravery will taste.
放他们走  桑琪
Let them go, Shenzi!
他们犯了一个错误  可怕的错误
They made a mistake, a horrible mistake!
但若你这样做  就会挑起跟木法沙的战争
But if you do this, you will start a war with Mufasa!
鬣狗和狮子有史以来
Hyenas and lions have been at war
就没有停止过交战
since the beginning of time.
但是木法沙的血脉将在这里结束
But Mufasa's bloodline will end here!
快跑
Run!
别让他们跑了
Don't let them get away!
快点
Come on!
你们听到了吗
Did you hear that?
未来的国王
The future king!
不要伤害我
Don't hurt me!
再来一次
Do it again!
如果你再敢靠近我儿子半步
If you ever come near my son again...
不会  木法沙  绝不
No, Mufasa. Never.
绝不会了
Never again.
桑琪  我警告过你了
You've been warned, Shenzi.
我以为你很勇敢呢
I thought you were very brave.
沙祖
Zazu?
带娜娜回荣耀石去
Take Nala back to Pride Rock.
遵命  陛下
Yes, sire.
别太难为他了  陛下
Don't be too hard on him, sire.
我记得曾经有一头任性的小狮子
I remember a cub, a certain headstrong cub...
经常陷入困境
who was always getting into scrapes.
但他取得了突出的成就
And he achieved some prominence,
对不对  陛下
did he not, sire?
我必须给我的儿子上一课
I have to teach my son a lesson.
娜娜  走吧
Nala, come along.
辛巴
Simba?
你故意违抗我的命令
You deliberately disobeyed me.
我知道
I know.
你可能会被杀死的
You could have been killed.
更糟糕的是  你把娜娜也置于险境了
And what's worse, you put Nala in danger.
你知道这之间的利害关系吗
Do you understand what's at stake?
你危及到了我们狮群的未来
You jeopardized the future of our pride.
我只是想让你知道我可以做到
I just wanted to show you I could do it.
我可以像你一样勇敢
That I could be brave like you.
我只在需要勇敢的时候勇敢
I'm only brave when I have to be,
别无选择的时候
when there's no other choice.
但是你什么都不怕
But you're not scared of anything.
今天我怕了
I was today.
真的吗
You were?
是的  我以为自己会失去你
Yes. I thought I might lose you.
就连国王也会害怕  对吧
I guess even kings get scared, huh?
比你想象的还要害怕
More than you could ever know.
-但你知道吗  -什么
- But guess what? - What?
我想那些鬣狗更害怕
I think those hyenas were even scareder.
那是因为没人敢跟你爸爸嚣张
That's 'cause nobody messes with your dad.
过来
Come here.
-爸爸  -怎么
- Dad? - Uh-huh?
我们是朋友  对吗
We're pals, right?
对
Right.
而且我们永远会在一起
And we'll always be together...
对吗
right?
辛巴  我要教你一件我父亲告诉我的事
Simba, let me tell you something my father told me.
你看那片星空
Look at the stars.
历史上所有伟大的国王
The great kings of the past...
都在浩瀚星空中俯视着我们
look down on us from those stars.
-真的吗  -是的
- Really? - Yes.
不论何时你觉得孤独
So whenever you feel alone...
就想想那些国王
just remember that those kings...
会一直在你身边引导你
will always be up there to guide you.
我也是
And so will I.
但我看不到他们  爸爸
But I can't see them, Dad.
继续寻找  儿子
Keep looking, son.
继续寻找
Keep looking.
木法沙好强
Mufasa is strong.
比我们强得多
Like, way stronger than us.
-请给我点空间  -什么
- Please give me some space. - What?
这么大个洞穴你躺在哪儿不行
You could lay anywhere in this cave.
-你想让我躺在哪儿...  -我需要个人空间
- Where do you want me to... - I need some personal space.
-好吗  -好的
- Okay? - Okay.
并不是要贬低你  你很厉害
Not to take anything away from you. You were great.
但是他...
But he is...
好吧  现在我知道你是故意的了
See, now I know you're doing this on purpose.
你也非常勇敢  强势  能量充沛
You're brave, too. Tough, good energy.
你这纯粹是恶意中伤了
Now you're just being spiteful.
姿势不错
Good posture.
下次让我看见木法沙
Next time I see Mufasa...
我要给他一个永远忘不掉的教训
I'm gonna teach him a lesson he will never forget.
你走运了  他就在你背后
Well, you're in luck! He's right behind ya.
木法沙
Mufasa?
那不是国王
That's not the king.
你们这些蠢货掠尽了自己领地的全部活物
You fools have stripped your land of every living thing.
然而我把两头小狮子送到你们手上
And yet I send two little cubs your way...
你们却让他们活着回去了
and they come back alive.
看来我们只能吃了你将就了
I guess we'll have to eat you instead.
为什么只看到一顿饭
Why eat one meal...
却放弃后半辈子都能大快朵颐的机会
when you can be feasting the rest of your lives?
你能给我们提供什么
What could you possibly offer us?
一个让你们填饱肚子的地方
A place where you can fill your bellies.
阳光照耀下的一切
Where everything the light touches
都归你们尽情杀戮
is yours for the kill.
荣耀大地可不是你说了算的
The Pride Lands are not yours to give.
国王控制着所有猎场
The king controls those hunting grounds.
所以我们要杀了他
That's why we're going to kill him.
在狩猎一事上
Mufasa has always shown too much restraint...
木法沙总是过于克制
when it comes to hunting.
等我成为国王
When I am king...
强者就可以予取予求
the mighty will be free to take whatever they want.
因为鬣狗的肚子永远填不饱
Because a hyena's belly is never full.
木法沙太强大了  难以挑战
Mufasa's far too powerful to challenge.
♪ 木法沙已是明日黄花 ♪
♪ Mufasa is yesterday's message ♪
♪ 一个腐朽  分崩离析的政权 ♪
♪ A clapped-out, distracted regime ♪
♪ 其衰败毫无疑问已被预言 ♪
♪ Whose failings undoubtedly presage ♪
♪ 我们需要不同的梦想 ♪
♪ The need for a different dream ♪
♪ 没错  狮子统治的时代正在变革 ♪
♪ Yes, leonine times are a-changing ♪
♪ 意味着鬣狗也必改变 ♪
♪ Which means that hyenas must too ♪
♪ 我的愿景更为清晰宽广 ♪
♪ My vision is clear and wide-ranging ♪
♪ 甚至也包含你们 ♪
♪ And even encompasses you ♪
♪ 准备好迎接世纪大政变 ♪
♪ So prepare for the coup of the century ♪
♪ 准备好迎接最为黑暗的诡计 ♪
♪ Prepare for the murkiest scam ♪
♪ 精心谋划 ♪
♪ Meticulous planning ♪
♪ 耐心等待 ♪
♪ Tenacity spanning ♪
♪ 几十年来的否定  所以我要 ♪
♪ Decades of denial is simply why I'll ♪
♪ 成为无可争辩的国王 ♪
♪ Be king Undisputed ♪
♪ 尊敬  拥戴 ♪
♪ Respected. Saluted ♪
♪ 认可我的才能 ♪
♪ And seen for the wonder I am ♪
♪ 没错  我的獠牙和野心一样赤裸 ♪
♪ Yes, my teeth and ambitions are bared ♪
♪ 准备好 ♪
♪ Be prepared ♪
♪ 没错  我们的獠牙和野心一样赤裸 ♪
♪ Yes, our teeth and ambitions are bared ♪
♪ 准备好 ♪
♪ Be prepared ♪
我爸爸很生我的气
My dad was pretty upset with me.
所以我们才要来这里  辛巴
That's why we're here, Simba.
我知道你怎样做才能向他弥补你的过错
I think I know a way for you to make it up to him.
一个让他忘记之前一切的礼物
A gift that will make him forget it ever happened.
但他是国王  我能送他什么呢
But he's the king. What could I give him?
你的咆哮
Your roar.
我的咆哮
My roar?
没错
Yes!
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
这个峡谷是所有狮子来练习咆哮的地方
This gorge is where all lions come to find their roar.
所有狮子
All lions?
我爸爸也是吗
Even my dad?
木法沙在你这么大的时候也来过这里
Even Mufasa came here when he was your age.
不肯离开
Refused to leave...
直到他的咆哮响彻云霄
until his roar could be heard above the rim.
一直到天上吗
All the way up there?
那时候你就知道自己练好了
That's when you know you've found it.
只要一点点练习
With a little practice...
就不会再被叫小狮子了
you'll never be called a cub again.
听好了
Watch this.
你会学会的  辛巴
You'll get it, Simba.
慢慢来
Just takes time.
我一会儿来看你
I'll check on you later.
爸爸会为我骄傲的  对吗
Dad will be so proud, won't he?
这是一个他永远忘不掉的礼物
It's a gift he'll never forget.
木法沙  快来
Mufasa! Quick!
峡谷里角马狂奔
Stampede in the gorge!
辛巴在下面
Simba's down there!
辛巴
Simba?
我去找他
I'll find him.
扎祖
Zazu!
坚持住  救援来了
Hold on! Help is coming!
他在那儿  那棵树上
There he is! On that tree!
我来了  辛巴  坚持住
I'm coming, Simba! Hold on!
我去帮他们  扎祖  你去叫狮群
I'll help them, Zazu! You get the pride!
快去
Go!
爸爸
Dad!
辛巴
Simba!
到我这儿来  儿子
Come to me, son.
跳
Jump!
爸爸
Dad!
疤面
Scar!
救救我
Help me.
国王万岁
Long live the king!
不
No!
爸爸
Dad?
快点  醒醒
Come on, wake up.
救命  救命啊
Help! Somebody help!
辛巴
Simba!
你干了什么
What have you done?
是角马狂奔
It was a stampede.
他想救我
He tried to save me.
这是个意外
It was an accident.
我不是故意的…
I didn't mean for it to...
你当然不是
Of course you didn't.
谁都不希望发生这种事
No one ever means for these things to happen.
但是国王已死
But the king is dead...
如果不是因为你…
and if it weren't for you...
他就还活着
he'd still be alive.
你父亲对你寄予厚望
Your father had such hopes for you...
给了你太多机会
gave you so many chances.
而你就这样报答他
And this is how you repay him.
我不知道  我不知道
I didn't know. I didn't know.
你母亲会怎么想
What will your mother think?
一个害死父亲的儿子
A son who causes his father's death.
一个杀死国王的孩子
A boy who kills a king.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
跑
Run.
逃跑吧  辛巴
Run away, Simba.
跑得远远的  再也别回来
Run away and never return!
杀了他
Kill him.
下去看看  确保他已经死了
Go down and make sure he's dead.
有没有搞错
Seriously?
对不起
I'm sorry.
现在距离很合适了
That's a good distance right there.
好的
Okay.
这么高摔下去没有幼崽能活下来
No little cub could survive that fall.
听着  我们就告诉她
Listen, we're gonna tell her...
我们下去了  然后把他吃了
we went down there and we ate him.
完美  因为我饿了
That's perfect, 'cause I am starving!
我们不是真要吃了他
We're not gonna eat him.
辛巴死了
Simba is dead.
她只需要知道这么多
That's all she ever has to know.
我看行
Works for me.
木法沙的死是个可怕的惨剧
Mufasa's death is a terrible tragedy.
荣耀大地上最伟大的领袖
The greatest leader the Pride has ever known.
失去兄弟
To lose a brother...
是沉痛深切的损失
such a deep, personal loss.
而小辛巴  他还那么年幼
And little Simba, who had barely begun to live.
这个幼崽的血脉关系到我们的未来
A cub whose blood held our future.
这痛苦难以承受
It's almost too much to endure.
我真希望我能及时赶到峡谷
I only wish I had gotten to the gorge in time...
去救他们
been there to save them.
而怀着沉重的心情
And so it is with a heavy heart...
我只能继承王位
that I must assume the throne.
木法沙和辛巴已死
Mufasa and Simba are gone...
所以我就是你们的国王
which means I am your king.
但我必须承认
But I must admit...
这个重任我无法独自承担
I cannot bear this burden alone.
我需要一些帮助来确保
And I will need some help to ensure
荣耀大地的安全
the safety of the Pride.
娜娜  跟紧点
Nala, stay close.
因此  从这场悲剧的灰烬中
And so, from the ashes of this tragedy...
我们将迎来新时代的曙光
we shall welcome the dawning of a new era.
一个伟大
A great...
辉煌的未来
and glorious future!
天呐
Oh, dear.
没撞到
I missed 'em!
总有一天我干掉一只秃鹫
I'm gonna get one of those vultures one day.
总有一天
I'm gonna get one!
我不明白这为什么对你这么重要
I don't know why it's so important to you.
我只是觉得这样会让我舒坦些
I just feel like it would make me feel better.
糟糕  是头小狮子
Oh, no. It's a little lion!
-这不是狮子  -那你去看看
- That is not a lion. - Well then, go check it out.
-是什么  -不是狮子  是只小鸟
- What is it? - That is not a lion, it's a furry bird!
看起来像狮子
It looks like a lion!
不是狮子  让我仔细看看  失礼了
That's not a lion. Let me get a closer look. Excuse me.
让我看看这是什么情况
All right, let me see what we're dealing with here.
是狮子
It's a lion!
-快逃命  彭彭  -等等  丁满
- Run for your life, Pumbaa! - Wait! Hey, Timon.
等等  丁满  是小狮子呀
Wait, Timon, wait! It's a little lion!
它会长大的
It gets bigger.
我们能留下他吗  好吗  拜托了
Can we keep him? Can we please keep him?
好的  我保证每天都遛他
Okay. I promise I'll walk him every day!
如果他弄出乱子  我来收拾
If he makes a little mess, I'll clean it up.
你才会是乱子
You'll be his little mess!
他会吃了你  然后用我身体当牙签
He's gonna eat you and then use my body as a toothpick!
但是等他长得高大强壮了
But one day, when he's big and strong,
他就会站在我们这边
he'll be on our side!
有了  如果他站在我们这边呢
I've got it. What if he's on our side?
听我说
Hear me out!
有头凶猛的狮子在身边或许不是坏主意
Having a ferocious lion around might not be such a bad idea!
那我们能留下他了吗
Well then, can we keep him?
可以  我们当然要留下他
Yes, of course we can keep him!
天呐  我们俩到底谁负责动脑
My God, who is the brains of this operation?
♪ 我们要给他取名弗雷德 ♪
♪ We're gonna name him Fred! ♪
你们是谁
Who are you?
-我们救了你的命  -是的
- We're the guys who saved your life. - Yes.
冒着生命危险  击退了愤怒的秃鹫
Risked everything. Fought off angry vultures!
很多秃鹫  一大群
Hordes of them. Flocks.
我是彭彭
I'm Pumbaa.
-这是丁满  -我有说我们救了你的命吗
- This is Timon. - Did I mention that we saved your life?
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
太消沉了吧
How bleak is that?
这都无所谓吗
It doesn't even matter?
难道我自己的麻烦还不够多吗
Like I don't have enough that I'm dealing with, right?
现在他的麻烦也得我解决吗
Now his problems are my problems?
但我们可以帮助他  我们有能力帮他
But we can help him. We're in a position to help him.
你是怎么了  尽量长话短说
So, how are you, in as few words as possible?
我干了坏事
I did something terrible.
我不想说
I don't wanna talk about it.
听着  孩子  我们都犯过错
Look, kid, we've all made mistakes.
一定有什么是我们能做的  对吧
There must be something we can do, right?
除非你能改变过去
Not unless you can change the past.
我说  这个要求有点高
Well, you know, that's a lot to ask...
-太难了  -说实话
- That's pretty hard. - if I'm being honest.
-难度太高  -改变过去
- That's a biggie. - I mean, change the past?
过去已经发生了
It already happened.
-所以无法改变  -但是
- Yeah, so you can't change that. -But
你知道什么是可以改变的吗
you know what you can change?
未来  这是我们的专长
The future. That's our specialty.
我们的特长
Kind of our thing.
还没发生的事要怎么改变啊
How can you change something that hasn't happened?
想要改变未来
Well, to change the future,
就得放下过去
you gotta put your past behind you.
抛得远远的
Way behind.
听着  小子  坏事无可避免
Look, kid, bad things happen
而你却无能为力  对吧
and you can't do anything about it, right?
对
Right.
错  如果世界背弃你
Wrong! When the world turns its back on you...
那你就背弃世界
you turn your back on the world!
只关注接下来的事情
And only embrace what's next!
把未知变成无所谓
And turn the "what" into "so what?"
爸爸可不是这么教我的
Well, that's not what I was taught.
那或许你需要新上一课
Well, then maybe you need a new lesson.
跟我学  小子  哈库那玛塔塔
Repeat after me, kid. Hakuna matata.
-什么  -哈库那玛塔塔
- What? - Hakuna matata.
哈库那玛塔塔
Hakuna matata.
哈库拉  大多数人一听到
Hakuna. Most people get a bigger reaction
就会很激动
when we say it the first...
-不管怎样  -还有人一听到
- Okay, well anyway. - Some people start clapping
-哈库那玛塔塔  -就立刻鼓掌
- Hakuna matata. - immediately.
意思是"无忧无虑"  一...
It means "no worries." One and a...
-好吧  -我来数拍子
- Okay. - I do the counting here.
-我想数  -不如我们一起数
- I wanna count! - Why don't we count together?
-好吧  好主意  -那好
- Okay, that's a good idea. - All right.
一  二...
One and a two and a...
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
♪ 多美妙的句子 ♪
♪ What a wonderful phrase ♪
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
♪ 不是一时狂热 ♪
♪ It ain't no passing craze ♪
♪ 它的意思是你此生不用再苦恼 ♪
♪ It means no worries for the rest of your days ♪
♪ 这是我们无忧无虑的 ♪
♪ It's our problem-free ♪
♪ 生活观 ♪
♪ Philosophy ♪
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
-哈库那玛塔塔  -对  我们的座右铭
- Hakuna matata? - Yeah, it's our motto.
座右铭是什么
What's a motto?
你说是什么就是什么
Nothin'. What's-a-motto with you?
漂亮
Nice.
这句话能解决你所有的烦恼
Those two words will solve all your problems.
对  以彭彭为例
Yeah. Take Pumbaa here.
♪ 他曾是头小疣猪 ♪
♪ Why, when he was a young warthog ♪
♪ 我曾是头小疣猪 ♪
♪ When I was a young warthog ♪
-你还好吗  -这故事让我百感交集
- How are you feeling? - It's an emotional story.
♪ 他发现自己的气味不太宜人 ♪
♪ He found his aroma lacked a certain appeal ♪
♪ 每餐之后他都能熏空大草原 ♪
♪ He could clear the savannah after every meal ♪
♪ 虽然我貌似皮糙肉厚 ♪
♪ I'm a sensitive soul ♪
♪ 但我内心纤细敏感 ♪
♪ Although I seem thick-skinned ♪
♪ 我好伤心  朋友从来不站在我的下风处 ♪
♪ And it hurt that my friends never stood downwind ♪
我一直在你身边而我讨厌那样
I was always here for you and I resent that.
♪ 我真丢脸 ♪
♪ And, oh, the shame ♪
对  他太丢脸了
Yes, he was ashamed
♪ 我想过改名字 ♪
♪ I thought of changing my name ♪
改成什么  "布拉德"吗
I mean, to what, "Brad"?
♪ 每次一放屁 ♪
♪ And I got downhearted ♪
♪ 我就心灰意冷 ♪
♪ Ev'ry time that I farted ♪
你不阻止我吗
Are you gonna stop me?
我不  你让我恶心
No, I'm not! You disgust me!
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
♪ 多美妙的句子 ♪
♪ What a wonderful phrase ♪
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
♪ 不是一时狂热 ♪
♪ Ain't no passing craze ♪
♪ 它的意思是你此生不用再苦恼 ♪
♪ It means no worries for the rest of your days ♪
♪ 唱起来  小子 ♪
♪ Yeah, sing it, kid ♪
♪ 这是我们无忧无虑的 ♪
♪ It's our problem-free ♪
♪ 生活观 ♪
♪ Philosophy ♪
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
欢迎来到寒舍
Welcome to our humble home.
你们住在这里
You live here?
我们想住哪儿就住哪儿
Well, we live wherever we want.
我们想做什么就做什么
We do as we please.
太美了
It's beautiful.
真的很棒  对吧
Yeah, it's really nice, huh?
大伙  这是辛巴
Everyone, this is Simba.
朋友  这是头狮子
That, my friend, is a lion.
食物怎么办
What about food?
你们打算怎么喂那玩意儿
Have you thought about feeding that thing?
是啊  我饿死了  我能吃下整匹斑马
Yeah, I'm starved! I could eat a whole zebra.
开始了
Here we go.
不不不  我们没有斑马了
No, no, no, kid, we're fresh out of zebra.
有羚羊吗
Any antelope?
不  听好了
No, listen, kid...
如果你想和我们一起生活  就得和我们吃的一样
if you want to live with us, you have to eat like us.
最重要的是  不要吃我们
And most importantly, not eat us!
看起来这里能弄到点虫子
This looks like a good spot to rustle up some grub!
-太棒了  -好极了
- Yeah! - It's perfect!
让开点  伙计们
Step aside, fellas!
这是什么
What's that?
太难嚼了
Too chewy.
这个有点坚果味
This one's got some nuttiness!
这就是我说的鲜味
Now that's what I call umami!
黏糊糊  但很可口
Slimy, yet satisfying.
特别脆
Extra crunchy.
-是当地的虫子  -是吗
- They're local. Yeah. - Oh, are they?
就是这里产的
They're from right there.
我跟你说  小子  这就是美好的生活
I'm telling ya, kid, this is the great life.
没有规则
No rules.
没有责任
No responsibilities.
奶油夹心的品种
The little cream-filled kind.
我超爱的
I love these!
-这种超棒的  -我超爱的
- Those are good. - I love these.
-这种最棒了  -能把头给我吃吗
- Those are the best. - Can I have the head?
怎么样  小子
Well, kid?
好吧
Oh, well.
哈库那玛塔塔
Hakuna matata.
黏糊糊
Slimy...
但很可口
yet satisfying.
-就是这样  -没骗你吧
- That's it! - We didn't lie!
卵囊  我找到一个卵囊
Egg sac! I got an egg sac!
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
♪ 它的意思是你此生不用再苦恼 ♪
♪ It means no worries for the rest of your days ♪
♪ 这是我们无忧无虑的 ♪
♪ It's our problem-free ♪
♪ 生活观 ♪
♪ Philosophy ♪
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
♪ Hakuna matata, yeah ♪
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
♪ 它的意思是你此生不用再苦恼 ♪
♪ It means no worries for the rest of your days ♪
♪ 这是我们无忧无虑的 ♪
♪ It's our problem-free ♪
♪ 生活观 ♪
♪ Philosophy ♪
♪ 哈库那玛塔塔 ♪
♪ Hakuna matata ♪
再来一遍
One more time.
不用了  我们唱够了
Oh, no, I think we did it. Yeah.
我们唱得很棒了
I think we got this one.
但我们刚刚进入最佳状态
But we're just getting in the groove, guys.
不  还是让他们意犹未尽吧
No, let's leave 'em wanting more.
是啊  从我们开始到现在你已经长了180公斤
Yeah, you've grown 400 pounds since we started.
而我一点都没变
Meanwhile I look exactly the same.
♪ 它的意思是你此生 ♪
♪ It means no worries ♪
你能让他别唱了吗
Will you tell him to stop?
是你非要我们唱这首歌
But you insisted we sing the song.
是我吗  明明是你起得头
I insisted? You started singing it!
这是我们的招牌歌曲
Well, it's our signature song...
-我们不应该分享  -看看这日落
- we shouldn't be sharing it with everyone. - Look at that sunset.
但这是我们的招牌歌曲  所以我们必须唱
But it's our signature song, so we have to.
让他别唱了好吗
Look, just tell him to stop.
♪ 它的意思是你此生 ♪
♪ It means no worries ♪
他开始即兴了  彭彭
Now he's riffing, Pumbaa.
简直是噩梦
This is a nightmare.
其实越唱越好了
It actually is becoming better and better.
娜娜
Nala.
过来
Come.
和我们一起坐
Sit with us.
沙祖  你去哪了
Zazu, where have you been?
很抱歉  娜娜  我已经尽快赶来了
I'm sorry, Nala. I came as soon as I could.
晨间报告  沙祖
The morning report, Zazu.
陛下  荣耀大地危在旦夕
Your Majesty, the Pride Lands are in imminent danger.
最后的畜群也要被鬣狗赶跑了
The hyenas are chasing off the last of the herds.
鸟回来了
The bird's back!
抓住他
Get him!
别回来了  除非你想被吃掉
Don't come here again, unless you want to be eaten!
我们必须做点什么  沙拉碧  我们必须战斗
We have to do something, Sarabi. We have to fight!
娜娜  疤面是国王
Nala. Scar is the king.
但你是我们的王后
But you are our queen!
趁现在还来得及  我们应该离开
We should leave before it's too late!
我们必须团结起来保护荣耀大地
We must all stay together and protect the Pride Lands.
这是我们的家  我们决不能放弃它
This is our home. We must never abandon it.
这不是我记忆中的家
This isn't the home I remember.
我们的时代会到来的  娜娜
Our time will come, Nala.
要有耐心
Be patient.
沙拉碧
Sarabi.
国王要见你
The king wishes to see you.
别去
Don't go.
我不怕他
I'm not afraid of him.
要与我共食吗  沙拉碧
Won't you join me, Sarabi?
食物多得很
There's plenty to go around.
你狩猎过度了  疤面
You're overhunting, Scar.
我只是完善了猎杀技巧
I've simply perfected the kill.
在我的军队的帮助下
With the help of my army.
你在屠杀一切
You're killing everything.
你还不明白吗  没有谁来挑战我
Don't you see? There is nobody to challenge me.
我们终于可以予取予求了
We can finally take whatever we want.
我们
We?
很久以前你选择了木法沙而不是我
Long ago you chose Mufasa over me.
但现在换了新国王
But now there is a new king.
所以不要这么自私
So stop being so selfish.
自私的是你
You are the selfish one.
其他狮子都指望着你
The other lions look to you.
只要你反抗  他们就会拒绝我
As long as you resist they will reject me.
站在我身边  我们将一起享受盛宴
Take your place by my side, and we will feast together.
我永远不会当你的王后
I will never be your queen!
那么从现在起
Then from now on...
狮子等鬣狗吃饱再进食
the lions will eat after the hyenas.
他们不会留下多少残渣
And they don't leave much behind.
你这是在干什么  小姑娘
Just what do you think you are doing, young lady?
走开  沙祖
Go away, Zazu.
我要去寻求帮助
I'm going to find help.
我绝对不会走开
I will very much not go away.
我发过誓要保护你
I am sworn to protect you
必须命令你回去睡觉
and must order you back to bed.
我不再需要保护了
I don't need protecting anymore.
疤面  很高兴见到你
Scar! Uh, wonderful to see you.
突然来访不好意思
Sorry to drop in like this!
我有没有告诉过你我哥哥
Have I ever told you about my brother
以为自己是只啄木鸟
who thought he was a woodpecker?
娜娜
Nala...
我会抓住你的
I'm gonna get ya!
我会抓住你的  我抓住了  抓住了
I'm gonna get ya! Oh, I got ya! I got ya!
辛巴  是你
Simba! It's you!
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
那只蝴蝶就在那里
Man, that butterfly was right there!
我差点就抓住他了
I almost had him.
我刚还以为是头狮子
I thought it was a lion.
就是  那种狮子
You know, the other kind of lion.
真正的狮子
You know, a real lion?
不是说你不是狮子
I mean, not that you're not a real lion.
我是说那种会吃...
But you know, the kind that eats...
我还是走吧
I'm gonna go.
你去哪儿
Hey, where you going?
你要吃虫子吗
You wanna get some grubs?
那家伙怎么了
What's up with that guy?
辛巴
Simba...
我该怎么说呢
How can I say this?
-他是猎物  -嗯
- He's prey. - Yeah.
他绝不想跟一个食肉动物玩耍
And he is never gonna want to frolic with a carnivore.
对  你们俩绝不会一起玩耍的
No. You two will never frolic.
为什么不行
Why not?
大自然的平衡是很微妙的
You see, in nature there's a delicate balance.
对  生命轮回  我知道
Yeah. The circle of life. I know that.
不  不  不
No. No, no, no.
我不知道你从哪里听说的"轮回"
I don't know where you're getting "circle" from.
对  才没有什么生命轮回
No, yeah. There's no circle of life.
-没什么轮回之说  -完全没有
- No, it's no circle. - No, not at all.
-事实恰恰相反  -对
- In fact, it's the opposite. - Yeah.
-是一条直线  -对
- It's a line. - Yeah.
一条无差别无意义的直线
It's a meaningless line of indifference.
我们都只是朝着直线走向终点
And we're all just running towards the end of the line.
总有一天我们会到达终点  就此结束
And then one day we'll reach the end, and that'll be it.
仅此而已  生命终结
That's it. Line over!
-什么都不会发生  -没错
- Nothing. - Nada.
你完全可以
And you can really just kinda...
做自己想做的事  只关心自己
do your own thing and fend for yourself...
因为你的生命之线不会影响到其他人
'cause your line doesn't affect anyone else's lines.
生活  然后死亡  就像这家伙一样
You're alive and then you're not. Like this guy.
真的不是轮回吗
You sure it's not a circle?
不是我们互相关联吗
That we're all connected?
轮回是指我们像这样
A circle would mean we're all this.
我所做的事会影响到他
That would mean what I do affects him...
-影响到那玩意儿  影响到那家伙  -不
- affects that thing, affects that thing. - Yeah. No.
-不是这样的  -这就意味着
- That's not how it goes. - Which would make
无论我们做什么事
doing whatever we wanted
都不怎么潇洒
not that cool.
我说得通俗点吧
Let me simplify this for you.
-生命是毫无意义的  -对
- Life is meaningless. - Yes.
所以你只需要关心自己就行了
That's why you just gotta look out for yourself.
所以你只要做自己  辛巴
That's why you do you, Simba.
是的  辛巴  这是我们第一次
Yeah, Simba, for the first time...
拜托你为我们安排今天的行程
we're entrusting you to make a plan for us today.
这很重要  想想你学过的那些
This is important. Think about all you've been taught.
你想做什么
What do you wanna do?
当然是  无所事事
Absolutely nothing.
就是这样  他明白了
Exactly! He gets it!
太棒了
Jackpot!
别挡着我  别挡着我
Out of my way! Out of my way!
-脆脆的  -开饭啦
- Crunchy! - All right! Time to eat!
好哇
Hello!
打得不错  辛巴
Nice one, Simba.
谢了  肯定是白蚁吃多了
Thanks. Must've been the termites.
或者蟋蟀
Or the crickets.
你还好奇我为什么喜欢睡在地下
And you wonder why I prefer to sleep underground.
丁满
Timon.
你有没有看着天上
Do you ever look up there
好奇那些闪耀的点点是什么
and wonder what those sparkly dots are?
彭彭  我不好奇  我知道
Pumbaa. I don't wonder. I know.
真的吗  它们是什么
Really? What are they?
萤火虫
They're fireflies.
萤火虫被卡在那个蓝黑色大东西上了
Fireflies that got stuck on that big, bluish-black thing.
好像有些道理
I guess that makes sense.
我一直以为它们是胀满气的气球
I always thought they were balls of gas
在亿万里外燃烧
burning billions of miles away.
彭彭  你怎么总是三句不离胀气
Pumbaa, why is everything always gas with you?
我知道
I know.
-你觉得呢  辛巴  -是啊
- What do you think, Simba? - Yeah.
我不知道
I don't know.
但我曾被告知
But somebody once told me...
历史上所有伟大的国王都在星空中
the great kings of the past are up there...
他们在守护我们
and they're all watching over us.
不错不错  真疯狂
That's a good one! That's insane!
真疯狂
That's insane!
王室亡魂在守护我们
Royal dead guys watching over us!
但愿他们不会从天上掉下来
Well, I hope they don't fall out of the sky!
坚持住  陛下  不要放手
Hang on, Your Majesty! Don't let go!
掉下来就糟了
That would be a mess.
-天啊  -辛巴  好好想想
- Oh, man! - I mean, Simba, think about it.
为什么一帮国王要守护我们
Why would a bunch of kings be looking out for us?
我们是异类
We're outcasts.
王室疣猪
Royal warthogs!
-我不行了  -我不行了
- I can't! - I can't!
-我不行了  -我真的不行了
- I can't! - I actually can't.
我不行
I can't.
不  你行  我不行
No, you can. I can't.
是啊  是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊  是挺蠢的
Yeah. That's... that's stupid.
我去找点虫子吃
I'm gonna go get some grubs or something.
你跟他说什么了
What did you say to him?
我不知道
I don't know.
你说的时候
As you were saying it,
我就想"这不会有好结果"
I thought, "This won't end well."
你就开始笑
You just start laughing.
你也笑了
You laughed too.
我没有  绝对没有
I did not. I would never.
老天  我搞砸了
Man, I blew it.
辛巴
Simba.
辛巴还活着
Simba is alive!
♪ 你是狮子 ♪
♪ A-weema-weh ♪
♪ 在丛林中  广阔的丛林中 ♪
♪ In the jungle, the mighty jungle ♪
♪ 狮子今夜入眠 ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ 在丛林中  寂静的丛林中 ♪
♪ In the jungle, the quiet jungle ♪
♪ 狮子今夜入眠 ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ 你是狮子 ♪
♪ A-weema-weh ♪
♪ 在村庄旁  平和的村庄旁 ♪
♪ Near the village, the peaceful village ♪
♪ 狮子今夜入眠 ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ 在村庄旁  安静的村庄旁 ♪
♪ Near the village, the quiet village ♪
♪ 狮子今夜入眠 ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ 你是狮子 ♪
♪ A-weema-weh ♪
♪ 你是 ♪
♪ A-wee ♪
彭彭
Pumbaa!
快逃命
Run for your life!
快跑  彭彭  快跑
Run, Pumbaa, run!
丁满  救命
Timon, help!
彭彭
Pumbaa!
Pumbaa?
我要死了
I'm gonna die!
我来了  彭彭  坚持住
I'm coming, Pumbaa! Hang in there!
让开  让开  让开
Move! Move! Move!
不
No!
不  不
No! No!
不
No!
娜娜
Nala?
辛巴
Simba?
真的是你吗
Is that really you?
是的
Yeah.
是我  辛巴
It's me, Simba!
娜娜  你怎么来了  天呐
Nala, what're you doing? Oh, my...
真不敢相信
I don't believe it!
瞧瞧你
Look at you!
彭彭
Pumbaa...
我想你不会被吃了
I don't think you're getting eaten.
你都去哪了
Where have you been?
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead!
你以为他死了  我还以为我要死了
You thought he was dead. I thought I was dead!
我以为你要吃了我
I thought you were gonna eat me.
真有趣
What fun!
抱歉  我想先问一句
I'm so sorry, before we move on,
你们俩是怎么认识的
how do you two know each other?
丁满  彭彭
Timon, Pumbaa...
来见见我最好的朋友娜娜
I want you to meet my best friend, Nala.
最好的朋友  伤心了
Best friend? Well, that hurts.
娜娜  你会喜欢这里的
Nala, you're gonna love it here!
这里特别棒
This place is amazing.
你想要的一切应有尽有
It's everything you could ever want.
辛巴  我们得离开这里
Simba, we need to leave.
疤面和鬣狗控制了一切
Scar has taken over with the hyenas.
你必须继承你的王位
You have to take your place as king.
国王  辛巴吗
King? Simba?
我们是你忠诚的仆从  向你下跪
We kneel before you as loyal servants.
彭彭  别激动  她说错了
Pumbaa, relax. She's wrong.
女士  你搞错狮子了
Lady, you've got your lions crossed.
漂亮
Nice.
再次见到你
Seeing you again,
你不知道这对大家意味着什么
you don't know what this will mean to everyone.
这对我意味着什么
What this means to me.
你必须回家
You have to come home.
这里就是我家
This is my home.
请你留下
Please stay.
这地方非常不可思议
This place is incredible.
我知道你会喜欢的
I know you'll love it.
我不能
I can't.
拜托
Come on!
至少让我带你到处转转
At least let me show you around.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
辛巴  这里好美
Simba, it's so beautiful.
♪ 我明白发生了什么 ♪
♪ I can see what's happening ♪
我不明白  什么
I can't. What?
♪ 他们仍不知晓 ♪
♪ And they don't have a clue ♪
他们是谁
Who's "They"?
♪ 他们会坠入爱河  结果是 ♪
♪ They'll fall in love and here's the bottom line ♪
♪ 我们仨只剩俩 ♪
♪ Our trio's down to two ♪
我懂了
I get it.
♪ 暮光轻柔抚摸 ♪
♪ The sweet caress of twilight ♪
是啊
Yeah.
♪ 到处弥漫魔法 ♪
♪ There's magic ev'rywhere ♪
到处都是
It's ev'rywhere.
♪ 在这浪漫的氛围中 ♪
♪ And with all this romantic atmosphere ♪
♪ 灾难即将来临 ♪
♪ Disaster's in the air ♪
♪ 今晚  你能感受到爱吗 ♪
♪ Can you feel the love tonight? ♪
♪ 还有夜晚带来的宁静 ♪
♪ The peace the evening brings ♪
♪ 此刻世界与其中万物 ♪
♪ The world for once in perfect harmony ♪
♪ 合而为一 ♪
♪ With all its living things ♪
♪ 有好多话想对她说 ♪
♪ So many things to tell her ♪
♪ 但怎么让她明白  我过往的真相 ♪
♪ But how to make her see the truth about my past? ♪
♪ 根本不可能 ♪
♪ Impossible ♪
♪ 她会离我而去 ♪
♪ She'd turn away from me ♪
♪ 他有话没说  有所隐瞒 ♪
♪ He's holding back, he's hiding ♪
♪ 但我无法知道是什么 ♪
♪ But what, I can't decide ♪
♪ 我能看到他内心有王的灵魂 ♪
♪ Why won't he be the king I know he is? ♪
♪ 可他为什么不愿当呢 ♪
♪ The king I see inside? ♪
♪ 今晚  你能感受到爱吗 ♪
♪ Can you feel the love tonight? ♪
♪ 还有夜晚带来的宁静 ♪
♪ The peace the evening brings ♪
♪ 此刻世界与其中万物 ♪
♪ The world for once in perfect harmony ♪
♪ 合而为一 ♪
♪ With all its living things ♪
♪ 今晚  你能感受到爱吗 ♪
♪ Can you feel the love tonight? ♪
♪ 无需考虑太远 ♪
♪ You needn't look too far ♪
♪ 就让我们度过这个变幻莫测的夜晚 ♪
♪ Stealing through the night's uncertainties ♪
♪ 爱就在那里 ♪
♪ Love is where they are ♪
♪ 如果他今晚坠入爱河 ♪
♪ And if he falls in love tonight ♪
♪ 那么不难猜到 ♪
♪ It can be assumed ♪
♪ 他与我们无忧无虑的日子将成往事 ♪
♪ His carefree days with us are history ♪
♪ 总之  我们的朋友完蛋了 ♪
♪ In short, our pal is doomed ♪
我说了吧  这里是不是很棒
I told you. Isn't it great here?
或许可以永远像这样
You know, maybe it could be like this forever.
这里很棒
It's amazing.
但有件事我不明白
But there's something I don't understand.
如果你一直以来都活着
If you've been alive all this time...
你为什么不回家
why haven't you come home?
我们真的很需要你
We've really needed you.
他们可以的
They're fine, all right?
根本不需要我
Nobody needs me.
你是国王
You're the king.
娜娜  疤面是国王
Nala, Scar is the king.
辛巴  他摧毁了荣耀大地
Simba, he's decimated the Pride Lands.
没有食物  没有水
There's no food, no water...
我无能为力
There's nothing I can do.
那你母亲呢
What about your mother?
这是你的责任
This is your responsibility.
你必须挑战疤面
You need to challenge Scar.
我不能回去  永远不能
I can't go back. Ever.
为什么
Why?
因为峡谷里发生的事吗
Because of what happened at the gorge?
疤面告诉我们
Scar told us that...
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand!
都不重要了  好吗
None of it matters. Okay?
哈库那玛塔塔
Hakuna matata.
什么
What?
这是我在这里学到的东西
It's something I learned out here, okay?
坏事无可避免
You see, sometimes bad things happen,
而你却无能为力
and there's nothing you can do about it.
那为什么还要操心
So, why worry?
为什么操心
Why worry?
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?
你不是我认识的那个辛巴
You're not the Simba I remember.
我也不会再是了  你满意了吗
And I never will be. Are you satisfied?
不  我很失望
No, I'm disappointed.
你这口气跟我爸一模一样
You know, now you're starting to sound like my father.
那很好  至少我没有迷失自我
Good. I'm glad one of us does.
你根本不知道我经历了什么
You have no idea what I've been through!
我是来这里寻求帮助的
I came here looking for help.
看来是我错了
I guess I made a mistake.
再见  辛巴
Goodbye, Simba.
"失望"
"Disappointed"?
她想让我回家
She wants me to go home?
我已经在家了
I am home.
"最好的朋友"
"Best friend"?
我不需要最好的朋友  我谁都不需要
I don't need best friends. I don't need anybody.
从来没需要过
Never did.
走开
Go away.
走开并无法回答这个问题
Going away will not answer the question.
什么问题  你是谁
What question? Who are you?
我知道我是谁
I know exactly who I am.
问题是  你是谁
The question is, who are you?
无名之辈而已  别烦我  好吗
I'm nobody. So leave me alone. All right?
每个人都有自己的身份  即便是无名之辈
Everybody is somebody. Even a nobody.
我觉得你搞混了
Yeah, I think you're confused.
我搞混了
I am confused?
你连自己是谁都不知道
You don't even know who you are.
这么说  你知道
And I suppose you do?
我抱过木法沙的儿子
I held the son of Mufasa.
你之前认识我父亲
You knew my father?
不对
Correction.
我现在也认识他
I know your father.
他很早就死了
He died a long time ago.
他还活着
He's alive!
我带你去找他
And I can take you to him.
跟我来  我带你去
Follow me. I will show you!
等等
Whoa. Hey, hey, hey!
如果你能跟上的话
If you can keep up!
等等
Wait!
跟着我
Follow me!
快  快  过来
Quickly, quickly! Come through!
你慢点
Slow down!
你最好快一点
You better hurry.
等等  我来了  我来了
Hold on. I'm coming, I'm coming.
来吧
Come.
你父亲在等你
Your father is waiting.
你看到他了吗
Do you see him?
我什么也没看到
I don't see anything.
再仔细看看
Look closer.
看到了吗
You see?
他永远活在你心里
He lives in you.
辛巴
Simba.
爸
Dad?
辛巴
Simba.
你必须要在生命的轮回中找到自己的位置
You must take your place in the circle of life.
我找不到
I can't.
你必须要记住自己是谁
You must remember who you are.
真正的国王
The one true king.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不知道怎样才能像你一样
I don't know how to be like you.
作为国王  我最引以为豪的是一件事
As king, I was most proud of one thing.
就是有你这个儿子
Having you as my son.
那是很久以前了
That was a long time ago.
不  辛巴  这是永恒的
No, Simba. That is forever.
别
Please.
别再离开我
Don't leave me again.
我从未离开过你
I never left you.
也永远不会离开你
And never will.
记住自己是谁
Remember who you are.
一定要记住
Remember.
我再问你一遍
And so, I ask again.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是辛巴
I am Simba.
木法沙的儿子
Son of Mufasa.
♪ 心中的力量 ♪
♪ Yeah Spirit ♪
♪ 天空为你而开颜 ♪
♪ Watch the heavens open ♪
♪ 心中的力量 ♪
♪ Spirit ♪
♪ 可曾听到它的召唤 ♪
♪ Can you hear it calling? ♪
辛巴
Simba?
走  你还等什么
Come on! What are you waiting for?
我们回家
Let's go home!
♪ 心中的力量 ♪
♪ Yeah Spirit ♪
♪ 天空为你而开颜  开颜 ♪
♪ Watch the heavens open open ♪
♪ 你的宿命近在咫尺 ♪
♪ Your destiny is coming close ♪
♪ 勇敢面对  无惧斗争 ♪
♪ Stand up and fight ♪
♪ 向遥远之地前进 ♪
♪ So, go in to a far-off land ♪
♪ 成就伟大的自己 ♪
♪ And be one with the great I am ♪
我之前不愿相信你说的
I didn't wanna believe you.
那你现在打算怎么办
So, what are you gonna do?
我父亲曾经告诉我  要保护
My father once told me to protect
阳光照耀下的一切
everything the light touches.
如果我不争取  还有谁愿意去做
If I don't fight for it, who will?
我愿意
I will.
此行会很危险
It's going to be dangerous.
危险
Danger?
我对危险嗤之以鼻
I laugh in the face of danger.
不是吧
It can't be!
你好  沙祖
Hello, Zazu.
陛下
Your Majesty.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
我们来了
We're here!
各位稍安勿躁  我们来了
Everyone, calm down. We're here.
支援来了
The backup has arrived!
你们怎么来了
What are you guys doing here?
-我们没有担心  -对  没有担心
- We were not worried! - No, not worried.
-因为没什么好担心的  -对  哈库那玛塔塔
- 'Cause no worries. - Nope. Hakuna matata.
只是有点在意  因为
We were concerned, because...
因为
Because, you know...
你是我们的朋友
You're our friend.
所谓的无差别无意义直线呢
What about the meaningless line of indifference?
我们只是在想
Well, we were thinking...
-线也可以弯曲一点  -说得好
- maybe it curves a little bit. - That's a good point.
辛巴  是这样
I mean, Simba, look,
我承认彭彭说的观点是错的
I'm happy to admit when Pumbaa's wrong...
这次就是其中之一
and this is one of those instances.
什么  这才不是我的观点
What? That wasn't my thing.
直线的事是你说的
You told me about the line.
等等
Wait, hold on.
这就是你要争取的地方吗
Now, this is the place you're fighting for?
是的  丁满  这里是我家
Yes, Timon. This is my home.
在那个可怕的巨石后吗
Is it behind that terrifying rock?
看来还有待修缮
Talk about your fixer-upper.
现在这样我也挺喜欢的
I like what you've done with it,
不过好像有点尸骸遍野
although a bit heavy on the carcass.
你看  有只鸟
Look. A bird.
丁满  彭彭  这是沙祖
Timon, Pumbaa, this is Zazu.
居然是海鹦鹉
It's a puffin.
有趣
Charming.
辛巴  我们会一直支持你
Simba, we are with you until the end.
任您差遣  王上
We are at your service, my liege!
跟我来
Follow me.
到处都是鬣狗
Hyenas everywhere.
希望能死得痛快点
I hope it's a quick death.
别被咀嚼太久
You know, just not a lot of chewing.
你打算怎么带我们
What's your plan for getting us
穿过这群恶心的守卫
past the slobbering guards?
活饵
Live bait.
真是个好主意
That's a great idea.
这群家伙对新鲜肉食毫无抵抗力
Those guys could never resist fresh meat.
我们只需要找一个又大
So all we need to do is find something that's, like, big...
又丰满  又可口的动物
and plump, and juicy.
比如角马
Maybe like a gnu?
为什么都看着我
Why is everyone looking at me?
我非常荣幸
It is with deepest pride
并且非常高兴
and greatest pleasure...
为你们献上
that we proudly present...
你们的晚餐
your dinner.
♪ 别客气 ♪
♪ Be our guest ♪
成功了  彭彭
It's working, Pumbaa!
我的老朋友
My old friend.
沙拉碧  你为什么要为难自己
Sarabi, why put yourself through this?
你只需要答应成为我的王后
All you have to do is be my queen.
你受苦是为了什么
You're suffering for what?
还在怀念过去的生活吗
The memory of a life you once knew?
还在想念你爱过的国王吗
A king you once loved?
我只是想让你明白  真正的国王是什么样的
I tried to make you understand what a true king can be.
疤面  真正的国王  是具有怜悯之心的
Scar, a true king's power is his compassion.
我比木法沙优秀太多了
I am ten times the king Mufasa was!
你根本不配与木法沙相提并论
You are nothing compared to Mufasa!
木法沙
Mufasa?
不可能
It can't be.
离我母亲远一点
Get away from my mother.
辛巴
Simba.
你还活着
You're alive?
怎么可能
How can that be?
我来了  母亲
I'm here, Mother.
我回来了
I'm home.
辛巴
Simba...
很高兴看见你
I'm so happy to see you.
还活着
Alive.
你最好给我一个理由
Give me one good reason
能说服我不把你撕烂
why I shouldn't rip you apart.
那我可有很多理由
I can give you more than one.
你看
You see...
他们都认我为王
they think I'm king.
我们不认
Well, we don't.
你的统治结束了  疤面
Your reign is over, Scar.
辛巴才是名正言顺的国王
Simba is the rightful king!
你要动他  先打败我们
If you wanna get him, you have to get through us.
你们都支持我吗  狮子们
Are you with me, lions?
选择权在你手上  疤面
The choice is yours, Scar.
要么退位  要么战斗
Step down or fight.
一定要诉诸暴力吗
Must this all end in violence?
我不想摊上杀害家族成员的罪名
I'd hate to be responsible for the death of a family member.
为夺取至亲的生命
To feel the shame of knowing...
而感到羞耻
I took the life of someone I love.
我已经全抛诸脑后了
I put all that behind me.
但他们对此的想法呢
But have they put it behind them?
你忠实的臣民知道你做了什么吗
Do your faithful subjects know what you've done?
他在说什么
What is he talking about?
看来你还没告诉他们你的小秘密
So you haven't told them your little secret?
辛巴
Well, Simba...
是时候坦白了
now's your chance to confess.
告诉他们  谁该为木法沙的死负责
Tell them who's responsible for Mufasa's death.
是我
It was me.
这不是真的
It's not true.
告诉我这不是真的
Tell me it's not true.
是真的  对不起
It's true. I'm sorry.
他承认了
He admits it.
凶手
Murderer!
不是的  那是场意外
No, no. It was an accident.
要不是你  国王就还活着
If it weren't for you the king would be alive.
他的死都是你的错  你还敢否认
It's your fault he's dead! Do you deny it?
我不是凶手
I'm not a murderer.
他杀死了自己的父亲  我们能相信他吗
We should believe a son who takes the life of a father?
他杀死了自己的国王  我们能相信他吗
We should believe a son who takes the life of a king?
他还抛弃了自己的母亲
A son who abandons his mother?
不  我
No. I'm...
你什么  说出来  你是国王吗
You're what? Say it! Are you the king?
不是  我
No. No, I'm...
-你是国王吗  -不是  我
- Are you the king? - No, I'm...
-你什么  说出来  -我是
- You're what? Say it! - I'm...
我是无名之辈
I'm nothing.
那就臣服于你的国王
Then bow to your king!
辛巴
Simba!
这情景真熟悉
This looks familiar.
我以前在哪见过
Where have I seen this before?
对了  我想起来了
Oh, yes, I remember.
这就是木法沙死前的情景
This is the way Mufasa looked before he died.
我往下看
I looked down...
看见了他眼中的恐惧
saw the fear in his eyes.
这就是我的小秘密
And here's my little secret.
是我杀了木法沙
I killed Mufasa.
不
No!
我的父亲
My father!
你的哥哥
Your own brother!
你怎么下得去手
How could you?
他先杀了木法沙
First he kills Mufasa...
现在他还想杀我
and now he wants to kill me!
是你杀了他
You killed him!
告诉他们真相
Tell them the truth!
不要相信他的谎言
Don't believe his lies!
疤面
Scar...
你告诉我们你没能及时赶到峡谷
you told us you didn't get to the gorge in time.
没错
That's true!
那你怎么能看见木法沙眼中的神情
Then how did you see the look in Mufasa's eyes?
凶手
Murderer!
杀光他们
Kill them all!
狮子们  进攻
Lions, attack!
辛巴
Simba!
彭彭  我觉得我们甩掉他们了
Pumbaa, I think we lost them.
真是太可怕了
That was terrifying.
你听到低吼声了吗
Do you hear a low growl?
看起来我们晚餐要吃猪肉了
Looks like we'll be having pig for dinner.
肥肥胖胖的
Plump and chubby.
胖
Chubby?
他刚刚是不是说我胖
Did he just call me chubby?
我真的觉得他刚刚说我"胖"
It sounded a lot like he just said "Chubby".
这真是大错特错  因为
Which would be a mistake because...
我不会为真实的自我而感到羞耻
I will not be made to feel ashamed of who I am!
糟糕
Oh, boy.
也许看见鬣狗我会逃跑
I may run from hyenas...
但是我永远勇于与恶霸斗争
but I will always fight a bully!
-你感觉好些了吗  彭彭  -是的
- You feel better, Pumbaa? - I do.
你把怒气都发泄出来了
You got that out of your system?
是的
I did.
这顿大餐我已经等了一辈子了
Now, this is a meal I've waited my whole life for.
我也一直在等
I've been waiting too.
而且我已经不是小狮子了
And I'm not a cub anymore!
为国王和王国而战
For king and country!
那只鸟
It's the bird!
我能搞定它
I got him! I got him!
来啊
Tally-ho!
不  他把我搞定了
No! He's got me!
他把我搞定了
He's got me!
抓住那只鸟
Get that bird!
拜托  我们好好谈谈
Please! Let's discuss this.
这招永远不会过时
That never gets old!
都结束了  疤面
It's over, Scar.
我求你发发慈悲
Have mercy. I beg you.
慈悲
Mercy?
你的罪行不可饶恕
After what you did?
都是鬣狗的错
It was the hyenas.
那些恶心的食腐动物逼我做的
Those revolting scavengers made me do it.
我本来打算把他们都杀了
I was planning on killing them all.
你骗了鬣狗
You fooled the hyenas.
正如你骗了我
Just like you fooled me.
辛巴
Simba...
你不会杀了自己唯一的叔叔吧
you wouldn't kill your only uncle.
不会  疤面
No, Scar.
我和你不同
I'm not like you.
辛巴
Simba...
你真是太高尚了
you are truly noble.
我会补偿你的
And I will make it up to you.
只要你告诉我该如何证明自己
Just tell me how I can prove myself.
告诉我你想让我做什么
Tell me what you want me to do.
跑
Run.
逃跑吧  疤面
Run away, Scar.
跑得远远的  再也别回来
Run away and never return.
是啊
Yes.
当然
Of course.
如你所愿
As you wish...
陛下
Your Majesty.
你赢不了的  疤面
You can't win, Scar!
这是我的王国
This is my kingdom!
我的宿命
My destiny!
朋友们
My friends.
虽然会花费一些时间
It will take some time,
但只要我们齐心协力  就能建立军队
but together we will build our army.
朋友吗
"Friends", huh?
你不是说我们都是"恶心的食腐动物"吗
I thought you said we were "Revolting scavengers"?
没错  而且你还想杀了我们
Yeah. That you wanted to kill us?
不
No.
不  让我解释
No, let me explain.
我只是想骗他
I was trying to fool him.
我们将一起统治这个王国
We will rule together!
疤面  你只说过一句真话
There's only one true thing you ever said, Scar.
"鬣狗的肚子"
"A hyena's belly...
"永远填不饱"
"is never full."
不
No!
陛下
Your Majesty.
一定要记住
Remember.
♪ 在这生命轮回 ♪
♪ Till we find our place ♪
♪ 无尽之路 ♪
♪ On the path unwinding ♪
♪ 寻得 ♪
♪ In the circle ♪
♪ 安居之所 ♪
♪ The circle of life ♪
♪ 生生不息 ♪
♪ Circle of life ♪
狮子王
Never Too Late - Elton John
♪ 力挽狂澜  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ It's never too late to turn things around ♪
♪ 拨开迷雾  路就在前方 ♪
♪ Recover, unravel the path to confound ♪
♪ 怀疑者和失败者满心绝望 ♪
♪ The doubters and losers that line up despair ♪
♪ 告诉你为时已晚  毫无希望 ♪
♪ Who tell you it's over, you're goin' nowhere ♪
♪ 永远为时未晚  我希望为时未晚 ♪
♪ It's never too late, I hope It's never too late ♪
♪ 回到正轨  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ It's never too late to get back on track ♪
♪ 不能力挽狂澜  也要尽力争取 ♪
♪ To get at least some, if not all of it back ♪
♪ 我以为我很快乐  有时确实如此 ♪
♪ I thought I was happy, and sometimes I was ♪
♪ 但悲伤同样也很重要 ♪
♪ But sadness is just as important because ♪
♪ 因为必须承载责任和希望 ♪
♪ Got to carry the weight and hope ♪
♪ 永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ It's never too late ♪
♪ 奋起抗争  远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to fight the fight ♪
♪ 坚定不移  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to keep the night ♪
♪ 赢得胜利  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to win the day ♪
♪ 摆脱困境  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to break away ♪
♪ 光阴似水  日月如梭 ♪
♪ Time will start to move too fast ♪
♪ 朋友  把握当下 ♪
♪ But time is now, my friend ♪
♪ 我早已启程 ♪
♪ I'm a long way from the start ♪
♪ 终点尚且遥远 ♪
♪ But further from the end ♪
♪ 永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Oh, no it's never too late ♪
♪ 重新振作  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ It's never too late to get up off the ground ♪
♪ 不必万众瞩目  不必众星拱月 ♪
♪ Don't have to be noticed, don't have to be crowned ♪
♪ 所作所为  无意隐瞒 ♪
♪ I did what I've done, and I don't try to hide ♪
♪ 失去良多  从未低头 ♪
♪ I've lost many things, but never my pride ♪
♪ 永远为时未晚  我知道为时未晚 ♪
♪ It's never too late, I know It's never too late ♪
♪ 奋起抗争  远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to fight the fight ♪
♪ 坚定不移  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to keep the night ♪
♪ 赢得胜利  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to win the day ♪
♪ 摆脱困境  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to break away ♪
♪ 光阴似水  日月如梭 ♪
♪ Time will start to move too fast ♪
♪ 朋友  把握当下 ♪
♪ But time is now, my friend ♪
♪ 我早已启程 ♪
♪ I'm a long way from the start ♪
♪ 终点尚且遥远 ♪
♪ But further from the end ♪
♪ 永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Oh, no, it's never too late ♪
♪ Never too late ♪
♪ 我曾说我没有时间 ♪
♪ I used to say I don't have time ♪
♪ 今晚我要安眠 ♪
♪ I'm sleepin' tonight ♪
♪ 无所事事就是头等大事 ♪
♪ A day doin' nothin' is doin' it right ♪
♪ 不急不急  顺其自然 ♪
♪ No hurry, no hurry, it takes as long as it takes ♪
♪ 反正无能为力 ♪
♪ You might as well sleep ♪
♪ 不如倒头大睡 ♪
♪ For all the difference it makes ♪
♪ 爱情  安宁  解脱  我都没有找到 ♪
♪ I didn't find love or the peace or the breaks ♪
♪ 这些不是借口  而是一连串的错误 ♪
♪ These aren't excuses, but a string of mistakes ♪
♪ 我不会回首 ♪
♪ I won't go back there ♪
♪ 决不回首 ♪
♪ Not going back there ♪
♪ 奋起抗争  远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to fight the fight ♪
♪ 坚定不移  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to keep the night ♪
♪ 赢得胜利  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to win the day ♪
♪ 摆脱困境  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to break away ♪
♪ 奋起抗争  远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to fight the fight ♪
♪ 坚定不移  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to keep the night ♪
♪ 赢得胜利  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to win the day ♪
♪ 摆脱困境  永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Never too late to break away ♪
♪ 光阴似水  日月如梭 ♪
♪ Time will start to move too fast ♪
♪ 朋友  把握当下 ♪
♪ But time is now, my friend ♪
♪ 我早已启程 ♪
♪ I'm a long way from the start ♪
♪ 终点尚且遥远 ♪
♪ But further from the end ♪
♪ 永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Oh, oh, it's never too late ♪
♪ It's never too late ♪
♪ 永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ Oh, never too late
♪ Oh, it's never too late
♪ 永远为时未晚 ♪
♪ No, it's never too late ♪